Welcome back to A&W. If you have vintage holiday
decor and have ever wondered if it's worth
anything, our next guest is here to help. We
welcome back antique appraiser Gary Germer.
Gary, great to see you.
Helen, you too.
So good to see you. Okay, these are really fun,
and I think it brings back memories for a lot
of people, which is what a
lot of antiques do, really.
Are you big in decorating
for Christmas yourself?
Yeah, a little bit. I mean, we've
got the tree up, we've got lights up,
we've got the ornaments on.
But you don't have to see your house
from space or something, right?
No, no, not at all. Not like that.
Tammy Hernandez, the producer, asked
me if I'd talk about vintage ornaments,
and I didn't have any, so I have to
shout out to my friend Randy Parman,
who loaned me part of his collection.
Yeah.
And what's interesting about these is you
can find great stuff at Target and new stuff,
but the old stuff does bring
back that memory, doesn't it?
It does, yeah. I love it.
I love it.
You want to find stuff that's of value.
You want to kind of go 1970s and older.
Yeah.
If you get before World War II, prices jump. Of
course, Victorian, it's going to be museum quality
stuff.
And people collect it for all
kinds of reasons, you know.
If you have an aluminum Christmas tree, you
need these hot pink ornaments right here.
These ornaments, oh my gosh.
You remember the old aluminum trees?
I totally remember aluminum trees,
and I remember these ornaments.
Yeah, and so now if you find a box of
ornaments that are from the 19, what?
60s, those were probably from.
Hot pink's the color this year everybody
wants in Christmas tree ornaments.
And Randy was telling me in a box like that,
he would be selling for about $25 to $35 in the
shops.
Okay.
And then these little trees.
Aren't they fun?
Those are German, probably early 20th
century, and they're made, you know,
so it's less of a commitment,
I guess, than doing a...
Well, you know, if you have a small
place, I think this is perfect.
What's interesting are the
ornaments on it, and I realize I...
Excuse me, this is bad television to be moving
things, but you'll see these little beaded ornaments
like that that are on there.
And those date, here's one here.
Those date from the late 19th
century, early 20th century, 1920s.
Czechoslovakian crystal
hand-blown glass beads.
I think that they, when I've seen them at
estate sales, when I'm running estate sales,
I think they're hopelessly ugly.
But the people who collect them, those are worth
serious money, and they're looking for them
in good condition,
because they're so expensive.
They're so fragile, they don't survive.
Again, those will sell anywhere from
$15 to $50, depending on the subject.
But I think what we mostly think of
on the ornaments are these up front,
and I hope they can get the count,
the German and then later Japanese hand-blown,
or excuse me, mold-blown ornaments that are all
different subjects.
Yeah.
Those are what everybody, a lot of
people like to collect and do it.
I actually have my
friend Mary who has 115.
She gets a couple every year and does her
tree with nothing but different ornaments.
Again, I mean, we think of these a big deal,
but if you have, in Grandma's Attic and find a
box full of these, you
could be into serious money.
Anything that looks like Halloween, like this
little spider one that's in the very front up
there.
I don't know if you can
show that to the folks.
Here we go.
Anything like that is through the moon.
That particular ornament, $50 to $75
just for that particular ornament.
Wow.
These other ones are anywhere
from $5 to $20 a piece range.
Okay.
This here is spun paper.
German.
Okay.
And you'd have to feel it's very delicate and
light, but it's made of like a spun silk paper.
That's really pretty.
Yeah.
A bicycle.
Some people only collect Santas, you know.
Yeah.
People break Christmas
down into subcategories.
They want variety maybe for their
tree, but they collect Santa clauses.
Uh-huh.
The most valuable ones usually are the German
ones, and I think the one in your hand is an old,
early 20th century German one.
Okay.
I think the Japanese ones were
made probably in the 30s and 40s.
Wow.
The old Santa in the boot is a German one.
Okay.
And those are from the 1920s to 30s.
So, again, they range from
anywhere from $50 to $100 a piece.
Right.
Okay.
And then the big Santa, this one, these
are the period, do you remember this?
I molded it and you said when we were
kids, they had these plastic faces on the-
Oh, yeah.
Look at that.
On the molded.
So, that's about a $50 to $75 Santa
Claus as well, but that's 1960s.
Oh, wow.
Again, that's a very old Santa Claus.
And I think it was to scare
children at Christmas.
I got you.
Snowmen, too.
You talk about people
collecting certain things.
And this is fun because what this is, is a,
and I can tell carefully taken apart here.
Don't break it, Gary.
It's not yours.
It's a candy container.
Oh.
So, you would get this in the candy store and
you would get it at Christmas and it would
be filled with Christmas candies for you.
Yeah.
And then you have this fun
little container to decorate.
And again, some people
just collect snowmen.
Snowmen are much harder
to find than Santas.
Okay.
And then here's another little
snowman made with a little.
Yeah, a little, made from a pine cone.
Pine cone, that's right.
That might have been a handmade
sort of a thing that somebody made.
But he's fun and full of glitter and all.
And then these ornaments right
here, I can't really see those.
Sorry, I'm quite.
Yeah.
Similar to these over here,
except a little bit newer.
And you'll find boxes of
the glass balls like this.
So, if you're going through your grandma's
attic or basement looking through Christmas
ornaments or you're at estate sales, don't
pass on the, you think, oh, they're just a
bunch of old ornaments.
They really can have some good
value and give a certain good look.
The collectors buy everything.
Even like here, we have.
Oh, gosh, I remember that.
The old tinsel, you'd
throw it onto the tree.
And don't smoke your cigarette now.
Back in the day.
And then wrap.
This was $25 for the tissue.
Yes, yes.
Never used it.
And so, sometimes I think people actually
will use this for a vintage Christmas or they
collect it just simply because
they collect Christmas stuff.
And Christmas oriented stuff.
Would something like this
actually get you something?
Oh, yeah.
Wow.
That would be $15.
I so remember that.
Yeah.
Okay, then there's a candle in the
middle that lays like a wreath.
These actually are,
they're a type of a velvet.
And they, if you look on the back, you can
actually wire them up and hang them to have
the hanging wreath.
They were made in Japan in the 1950s and
are certain collectible unto themselves.
Again, in the 50s.
$50 range on that particular piece.
What I brought was stuff
you're going to find.
I mean, there's a lot of really rare stuff
that can go into the thousands of dollars,
you know, museum type stuff.
But nearly everybody's grandmother's
attic is filled with stuff like this.
Absolutely.
So, do not dismiss it if
you're doing house cleaning.
One last thing.
Tell me about this one.
Oh, these were little candy containers.
Oh, okay.
Again, that you'd hang on the
tree, something like a stocking.
Yeah.
And you would then fill it.
This is all paper, 1910 era.
Hard to find.
Because they crush and
they're very fragile.
Yeah.
And for a collector, they
pay about $40 to $60.
The little tree, I had a
friend who does just birds.
And these are Czechoslovakian
blown glass birds.
See, I like the birds.
And they clip on.
And I think for having a little tree like
this filled with birds for Christmas is kind
of a fun idea.
Yeah, I actually, these are like one
of my favorites, the clip-on birds.
Yeah.
Gary, this was fun.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate it.
By the way, if you'd like to get a hold of
Gary, we're going to put a link on our website
at katu.com.
Thanks, Ellen.
Thank you so much.
Always good to see you.
Good to see you.
All right.
We'll be right back
with more AM Northwest.
Don't go away.
We'll be right back.